Welcome back.
잘 돌아왔어요
So we've been doing the thoroughly distasteful, unsavory work of feature engineering.
그래서 저희는 완전히 불쾌하고 불쾌한 기능들을 작업해왔어요
Very grotty, uh, work.
아주 지저분한 일이죠
But I still find it a bit fun, I have to confess.
그래도 비트는 좀 재미있어요
But it's quite, quite, uh, hacky and involves getting very deep into the data.
하지만 좀 허접하고 데이터에 깊이 들어가야 해요
We went through a bunch of stuff to figure out the weights of items in our data set and stuff in an
데이터에 있는 물건의 무게를 알아내려고 여러 가지를 살펴봤어요 무게를 못 찾으면
average weight if we can't find the weights.
평균 무게를 계산했고요
Um, we're now going to look at the best sellers rank for each of our items.
이제 각 제품의 베스트셀러 순위를 살펴볼게요
And so we're going to try and collect best sellers rank from its features.
그래서 특징을 기준으로 베스트셀러 순위를 모을 거예요
Uh, and then uh, what comes back is in fact itself a dictionary, because a product on Amazon can
그리고 돌아오는 건 사실 사전이에요 아마존 제품 하나가 여러 베스트셀러
actually be ranked against multiple different bestsellers lists.
목록과 순위를 매길 수 있거든요
Um, and so we're going to do something again, very rough and ready.
그래서 다시 한번 거칠고 준비된 걸 해볼게요
And if it's features in multiple bestsellers lists, we're just going to take the average if it ranks
여러 베스트셀러 목록에 속성들이 있다면 평균을 선택해서 한 목록에서 1위 다른
first in one list and 10,000in another, we're just going to take the midpoint.
목록에서 10,000위인 경우 중간 지점을 선택할게요
We're which is we're just going to take the the one around the 5000 mark.
5천 마크에 해당하는 걸 가져갈 거예요
Uh, so this this is, it's it's, uh, it's all a little bit of guesswork.
비트 박스는 추측일 뿐이에요
Um, it's a bit of trial and error.
비트 박스는 시행착오를 거치죠
And often this kind of traditional data science is a bit like this, actually.
전통적인 데이터 과학은 사실 비트 박스와 비슷해요
So as we'll discover, is the modern data science as well.
현대 데이터 과학도 마찬가지죠
There's plenty of trial and error.
시행착오가 많아요
Typically, what you do with this, this kind of technique is that you try lots of features.
일반적으로 이런 기술로 하는 건 많은 기능을 시도해보는 거죠
You might try taking the average, or you might try taking the best and a few other things.
평균을 택하거나 최고를 택하거나 다른 걸 택할 수도 있죠
And you shove all of these features in there and you see which one wins out.
이 모든 기능을 밀어 넣으면 어떤 게 이기는지 알 수 있죠
Now, in this case, we're just going to pick the average.
이 경우엔 평균을 선택할게요
But if you've got the stomach for it and you're enjoying this, this, as I say, slightly distasteful
하지만 배짱이 있고 이 과정이 즐겁다면... 이렇게 여기저기 파헤치는
work of digging around in features, then try some more features.
게 좀 별로라면 다른 것도 해 보세요
Try adding in the minimum rank, the maximum rank, uh, whatever you wish, um, to see what gives
최저 계급이든 최대 계급이든 원하는 걸 추가해 보세요 가장 신호가 강한 게
the most signal.
뭔지 보게요
So in our case, we picked the average rank.
그래서 저희는 평균 등급을 뽑았어요
We just do it.
그냥 하는 거예요
And we're then going to to do the same trick we did with weights.
추로 했던 것과 같은 기술을 할 거예요
We're going to find out what is the average of our average ranks, which turns out to be that slightly
평균 등급을 계산해 볼게요 380,000명이라는 다소
curious number of 380,000 or so.
신기한 숫자가 나왔네요
And then we're going to give ourselves a get rank with default function, which tries to get a rank.
그런 다음 기본 함수로 get-rance를 줍니다 기본 함수는 랭크를 얻으려 하죠
And if something doesn't have a rank, it gives you the average, the average rank from the training
순위가 없는 것들은 평균을 줍니다. 훈련 데이터에서 평균 순위를
data set.
주죠.
Okay.
네
And then one more feature I'm going to add into the mix that I didn't mention before.
전에 말씀드리지 않은 기능이 하나 더 있어요
Uh, you may have guessed, I don't know is I'm going to say how long is the test prompt with all of
추측하셨을 수도 있는데 모든 세부 사항이 담긴 테스트 프롬프트가 얼마나 긴지
the detail that it's got in there?
여쭤보려고요
I don't know if you remember, there was that scatter diagram that we did, uh, a couple of days ago,
기억하실지 모르겠지만 며칠 전에 했던 분산도표가 있는데 빨간
or maybe just one day ago, uh, with lots of red dots on it that was trying to see, is there any correlation
점이 많이 있는 그 도표는 가격과 텍스트의 양 사이에 상관관계가 있는지
between the price and the amount of text?
알아보려고 했었죠
And when we looked at that visually, it appeared that there was a slight correlation.
시각적으로 봤을 때 약간의 상관관계가 있는 것 같았어요
I probably got that up.
제가 올렸을 거예요
We can just take a quick peek at that to see, oh no, it's not there anymore.
잠깐 살펴보면 이런, 이제 없네요
I've cleared it out.
다 치웠어요
You'll have to look back yourself if you ran it.
당신이 운영하면 당신이 돌아봐야 할 거예요
I hope you did go back and look at that red diagram again and you'll see what I mean.
다시 돌아가서 빨간 도표를 보면 무슨 뜻인지 알 거예요
There is a slight correlation there.
약간 상관관계가 있어요
So let's add that in.
이걸 추가하죠
Let's get get text length and we'll use that as well.
텍스트 길이 get get 그것도 사용하죠
And then the final one we're going to look at the brands.
마지막은 브랜드를 볼 거예요
Let's first look at the most common 40 brands.
가장 흔한 40가지 브랜드부터 살펴보죠
So we're going to count them all up using the same approach as before.
아까와 같은 접근 방법으로 모두 세어볼게요
Brands most common 40.
가장 흔한 브랜드 40개요
Let's look at the most common 40 brands.
가장 흔한 40가지 브랜드를 보죠
Here they are.
여기 있네요
And what you'll notice here is that there's a few, um, automobile car related brands, which I'm not
여기 보시면 자동차 관련 브랜드가 몇 개 있는데 제가 잘 모르는 것들이에요
You may be more knowledgeable than me.
저보다 더 잘 아실지도 몰라요
You may.
그러세요
You may think I'm missing a trick.
제가 뭘 놓쳤다고 생각하시겠죠
You may say, oh, there's a beautiful feature there that we could engineer of looking at top auto brands,
최고의 자동차 브랜드에서 볼 수 있는 멋진 기능이 있다고 할 수도 있죠 그런
in which case you should create that feature, add it in and see how you do.
경우 해당 기능을 만들어 추가하고 어떻게 하는지 보세요
Uh, I sadly don't have that domain expertise.
안타깝게도 전 그런 분야는 잘 몰라요
Um, and so what I've plucked out is a little category called top electronics brands, where I have
그래서 제가 고른 건 일류 전자 제품 브랜드예요 HP,
shoved in things like HP, Dell, Lenovo, Samsung, Asus, Sony, canon, Apple, Intel which I've
델, 레노버 삼성, 소니, 캐논, 애플 같은 제품을
just plucked out of here into this category.
이 카테고리에 넣은 거죠
And then that gives me a feature is Top Electronics brand.
그럼 톱 일렉트로닉스 브랜드의 기능이 생기죠
And this is one where again, I've done one feature.
이건 제가 한 가지 기능을 끝낸 거예요
You could come up with a bunch of features.
여러 가지 기능을 생각해낼 수 있어요
You could you could pick out different kinds of brands.
여러 가지 브랜드를 고를 수 있어요
You could pick out some auto brands.
자동차 브랜드를 골라요
You can create as many features as you want.
원하는 만큼 많은 기능을 만들 수 있어요
There's no harm in having more features, because the regression model is going to decide which of the
기능이 더 있다고 나쁠 건 없어요 회귀 모델이 어떤 기능이 신호를
features actually gives you some signal.
주는지 결정하거든요
And so a fun competition for you is to be generating features and see how well you can do with handcrafted
재미있는 대회는 기능을 생성하고 수공예 기능을 얼마나 잘 만드는지 보는
features.
거예요
I'll make one more important observation I mentioned a moment ago.
아까 중요한 걸 하나 더 말씀드릴게요
I don't have the car expertise, which means I can't pluck out auto brands.
자동차 전문가가 아니니 자동차 브랜드를 고를 수 없죠
And that leads to an interesting point, which is in this kind of traditional data science, it was
여기서 흥미로운 점이 등장하는데 전통적인 데이터 과학에서는
important that data scientists had some strong knowledge of the domain they were working in.
데이터 과학자가 자신이 연구하는 분야에 대해 어느 정도 아는 게 중요했어요
If you were working in products you needed to understand about different products.
제품을 다루는 일을 한다면 다양한 제품을 이해해야 해요
You needed to understand about different car manufacturers, because you needed to know which features
여러 자동차 제조사를 이해해야 했어요 어떤 기능을 설계해야
to engineer to have the most likely chance of success.
성공 확률이 가장 높을지 알아야 했으니까요
One of the curious and remarkable surprises of deep neural networks and modern machine learning and
현대 딥 뉴런네트워크와 머신 러닝 딥 러닝이 가진 신기하고 놀라운 점은
modern modern deep learning is that the model figures out for itself which features matter.
물질을 포함한 모델이 스스로 만들어 낸다는 거예요
And so there's no longer this requirement for data scientists like you and me to have deep domain expertise
따라서 여러분이나 저 같은 데이터 과학자가 모델을 구축하는 분야에서 딥 도메인 전문성을
in the field that we were building models around, because we just have to have expertise in how to
가질 필요가 더는 없습니다 llms와 모델을 구축하는
build llms and models and both of any kind of deep neural network.
방법과 심층 신경망 구축에 관한 전문성이 있어야 하니까요
And they have billions of parameters, and they are able to use the the understanding power of all of
수십억 개의 매개 변수를 가지고 있고 그 모든 매개 변수의 힘을 이용해서
their parameters to learn about the business area.
비즈니스 분야를 배울 수 있죠
But back in the day, in feature engineering, one had to understand it oneself and make things like
하지만 과거 피처링 엔지니어링에서는 스스로를 이해해야 했고 톱 전자
top electronics, brands features which we have done.
공학이나 브랜드 같은 기능을 만들어야 했어요
And all of this brings us to this function here.
이 모든 게 이 함수로 연결돼요
Get features.
get 피처링이요
It takes an item and it creates this nice little dictionary here with a weight, a rank, a text length,
항목을 하나 골라 멋진 사전을 만듭니다 중량, 순위, 텍스트 길이
and an is top electronics brand, which is either a one or a zero.
1이나 0으로 된 톱 전자 제품 브랜드가 있죠
Um, and that, that is uh, our features group for this first model.
이게 첫 번째 모델의 특징 그룹이에요
The first real model that we're building.
우리가 만드는 첫 번째 모형이죠
Uh, and please, I urge you to, to spend some time turning this into your features of your dreams.
그리고 부디 시간을 들여 이걸 꿈의 형태로 바꿔 보세요
Uh, see how well you could do by engineering features.
엔지니어링 기능으로 얼마나 잘할지 보는 거죠
And you can probably do quite well.
잘할 수 있을 거예요
Um, but I don't think you'll be much of a match for what's to come.
하지만 앞으로의 일에 비하면 상대도 안 될 거예요
But give it a try.
그래도 한번 해 봐요
Now.
지금요
Give it your best shot.
최선을 다해 봐요
But after this, uh, this coming up in this next video, we will actually run.
하지만 이다음에 나오는 다음 영상에서는 실제로 달릴 거예요
This run our traditional machine learning model and see how it fares.
전통적인 머신 러닝 모델을 실행해 보고 결과를 보죠
I will see you then.
그때 봐요